Guide to the Dorothy Richardson Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Special Files, Series III; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - CLIPPINGS OF ARTICLES BY DOROTHY RICHARDSON
    - ADVENTURE FOR READERS, Life and Letters To-day, vol. 22, no. 23, p. 45-52., 1939 Jul (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - AFTERNOON TEA. Poem extracted from Queen., 1932 Dec 28 (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - AMATEUR EVIDENCE IN DIETETICS. The Dental Record, p. 300-303. (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - ANTHEIL OF NEW JERSEY. Vanity Fair, p. 136 & 138., 1925 Nov (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - ARTIST & THE WORLD TODAY. Bookman, p. 94., 1934 May (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - AUGUST. Saturday Review, vol. 114, no. 2962, p. 142., 1912 Aug 3 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - BORED WIVES - WHERE IS MISS JAMESON'S SUBURBIA?, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - BROTHERS RABBIT AND RAT. The Contributor's Club, p. 247-249. (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - COMMENTS BY A LAYMAN. The Dental Record, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 226)
      - p. 10-11, 13, 19-20, 33-35, 57-58, 87-89, 99-101, 110-112, 119-121, 136, 140-142, 161-163, 169-170, 178, 190-192, 214-216, 221-222, 247-248, 262-264, 264, 310-312, 321-322, 350-352, 357-358, 375-376, 391-392, 427-428, 427-429, 483-486, 509-510, 541-544, 577-579, 606-607, 655-657, 686-688, 752-754., n.d.
    - DANS LA BISE. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - DAYS WITH WALT WHITMAN. The Crank, p. 259-263., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - DENTAL LEGISLATION AT GENEVA. The Dental Record, p. 161-162., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - DIET AND TEETH. The Dental Record, p. 553-556. (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - THE DOG AND THE POSTMAN. The Animal World, p. 125., 1947 Nov (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - DUSK. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - EN PAYS DE VAUD., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - THE END OF THE WINTER. Saturday Review. (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - EXCURSION. English Story: Sixth Series, p. 107-112., 1945 (Box 10, Folder 235)
    - THE FORSYTH DENTAL INFIRMARY FOR CHILDREN. The Dental Record, p. 336., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - A FRENCH UTOPIA. Ye Crank, p. 209-214., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - THE FUTURE IN AMERICA. Ye Crank, p. 95-99., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - GIFT, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - GRUYERES. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 240)
    - HAVEN. Life and Letters To-day, vol. 43, no. 84, p. 97-105., 1944 Aug (Box 10, Folder 241)
    - HAVEN. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 242)
    - HAY-TIME. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - THE HOLIDAY. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - IN THE DAYS OF THE COMET. The Crank, p. 372-376., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - IN THE GARDEN. The Queen, p. 11., 1924 Jul 2 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - JOURNEY TO PARADISE. Fortnightly Review, New Series, vol. 123, no. 735, p. 407-414., 1928 Mar 1 (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - LEADERSHIP IN MARRIAGE. The Contributor's Club, p. 345-348., 1925 (Box 10, Folder 248)
    - LODGE NIGHT. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 249)
    - MAGIC AND THE TOOTH. The Dental Record, p. 903-904. (Box 10, Folder 250)
    - MARCH. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 251)
    - MEDICAL AUSTRIA IN THE ARENA. THE ENCROACHING LAITY. The Dental Record, p. 143. With: Bernhard Berger, MEDICAL AUSTRIA, p. 217-218., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 252)
    - MESSAGE. Outlook, p. 256., 1927 (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - MR. CLIVE BELL'S PROUST. New Adelphi, vol. 2, no. 2, p. 160-162., 1928-9 (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - NEEDLESS WORRY. p. 160-162., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 255)
    - NIETZSCHE. The Open Road, p. 243-248 (2 copies)., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - NOVELS. p. 188-192., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 257)
    - NOVELS. Life and Letters To-day, p. 188-189., 1936-7 (Box 10, Folder 258)
    - THE OPEN ROAD. The Open Road, p. 153-158., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 259)
    - PEACH HARVEST. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 260)
    - THE PERFORATED TANK. Fanfare, p. 29., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 261)
    - A PLEA FOR A STATISTICAL BUREAU. The Dental Record, p. 403-405., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 262)
    - THE READING OF "THE JUNGLE". The Crank, p. 290-293., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - THE REALITY OF FEMINISM. The Ploughshare, p. 241-246., 1917(?) (Box 10, Folder 264)
    - RESOLUTION. Purpose, 1929, p. 7-9., 1929 Jan-Mar (Box 10, Folder 265)
    - THE RESPONSIBILITY OF DENTISTRY. The Dental Record, vol. 33, no. 10, p. 633-635., 1913 Oct 1 (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - THE RUSSIAN AND HIS BOOK. The Outlook, p. 267-268., 1902 Oct 4 (Box 10, Folder 267)
    - SCIENCE AND LINGUISTICS. The Dental Record, p. 149-150. (Box 10, Folder 268)
    - A SCULPTOR OF DREAMS. Adelphi, vol. 2, no. 5, p. 422-427., 1924 Oct (Box 10, Folder 269)
    - A SHEAF OF OPINIONS. Ye Crank, p. 153-157 (2 copies)., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 270)
    - SOME THOUGHTS SUGGESTED BY THE AUSTRO-HUNGARIAN PROBLEM. The Dental Record, p. 519-523., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - A SPANISH DENTIST LOOKS AT SPAIN. The Dental Record, p. 343-345., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - THE STORY OF A GOLDEN TOOTH, 1593. The Dental Record, p. 374-375., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 273)
    - A STRANGER ABOUT. English Story: Ninth Series, 1949, p. 90-94. (Box 10, Folder 274)
    - STRAWBERRIES. Saturday Review, vol. 113, no. 2956 p. 778-779., 1912 Jun 22 (Box 10, Folder 275)
    - SUMMER., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - A SUSSEX AUCTION. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - A SUSSEX CARRIER. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 278)
    - A TALK ABOUT TALKING. Life and Letters To-day, vol. 23, no. 27 [i.e.28], p. 286-288., 1939 Dec (Box 10, Folder 279)
    - THREE POEMS. Poetry: A Magazine of Verse, vol. 27, no. 2, p. 67-69., 1925 Nov (Box 10, Folder 280)
    - A VILLAGE COMPETITION. Saturday Review., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - VISIT. Life and Letters To-day, vol. 46, no. 97, p. 173-181., 1945 Sep (Box 10, Folder 282)
    - VISITOR. Life and Letters To-day, vol. 46, no. 97, p. 167-172., 1945 Sep (Box 10, Folder 283)
    - WANTED: THE PLAY-SPIRIT. Plain Talk, p. 5-6., 1913 Jul (Box 10, Folder 284)
    - WELCOME. Saturday Review, vol. 113, no. 2951, p. 620-621., 1912 May 18 (Box 10, Folder 285)
    - THE WIND. Saturday Review. (Box 10, Folder 286)
    - WOMEN AND THE FUTURE. Vanity Fair, vol. 22, no. 2, p. 39-40 (2 copies)., 1924 Apr (Box 10, Folder 287)
    - WOMEN IN THE ARTS. Vanity Fair, vol. 24, no. 3, p. 47, 100., 1925 May (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - YEATS AND BLOOMSBURY. St. Pancras Journal, vol. 12, no. 5, p. 67-70., 1958 Oct (Box 10, Folder 289)
    - YEATS OF BLOOMSBURY. Life and Letters To-day, vol. 21, no. 20, p. 60-66., 1939 Apr (Box 10, Folder 290)
  - CLIPPINGS OF ARTICLES ABOUT DOROTHY RICHARDSON
    - (clippings), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 291)
    - (clippings), 1922 Oct 31 (Box 11, Folder 292)
    - (clippings), 1931 Oct 22 (Box 11, Folder 293)
    - (clippings), 1940 Apr 26 (Box 11, Folder 294)
    - 2 copies, 1948 Dec (Box 11, Folder 295)
    - (clippings), 1951 Dec 28 (Box 11, Folder 296)
    - (clippings), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 297)
    - (clipping), 1953 (Box 11, Folder 298)
    - (clippings), 1957 (Box 11, Folder 299)
    - (clippings), 1958 Sep (Box 11, Folder 300)
    - (clippings, photocopy), 1963 (Box 11, Folder 301)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT DOROTHY RICHARDSON'S WORKS
    - CHRISTMAS DAY, 1957 Dec 30 (Box 11, Folder 302)
    - CLEAR HORIZON, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 303)
    - DAWN'S LEFT HAND, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 304)
    - OBERLAND, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 305)
    - PILGRIMAGE, 1921-57, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 306)
    - POINTED ROOFS, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 307)
    - THE TUNNEL, 1919-56 (Box 11, Folder 308)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT PEOPLE CONNECTED WITH DOROTHY RICHARDSON
    - Allinson, Adrian, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 309)
    - Austen, Jane & Forster, E.M., 1956 Nov 1 (Box 11, Folder 310)
    - Hale, Jessie A., n.d. (Box 11, Folder 311)
    - Odle, Alan, 1923, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 312)
    - Trotter, Wilfred, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 313)
    - Yeats, William Butler, 1951 Jun (Box 11, Folder 314)
  - LEGAL AGREEMENTS
    - Kenkyusha, Ltd, firm, publishers, Tokyo, 1933 Aug 18 (Box 11, Folder 315)
      [Agreement between Kenkyusha, Ltd and Gerald Duckworth & Co Ltd to publish in Japan a Japanese-annotated edition in English of Dorothy Richardson's The Pointed Roofs ]. Typed copy, 1 p.
    - Odle, Alan Elsden and Dorothy Miller Richardson, 1963 Aug 23 (Box 11, Folder 316)
      Certified copy of an entry of marriage [between Alan Odle and Dorothy Richardson, August 29, 1917] photocopy, 2 p.
    - Wells, Herbert George, 1927 May 13 (Box 11, Folder 317)
      [Deed guaranteeing Dorothy Richardson an income of £4.3.4. each month for the rest of her life, to be paid by H. G. Wells] Typed copy, 1 p.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 318)
      Young woman seated on bench Portrait of same young woman Portrait of older woman Portrait of man Group (8 persons) Group (10 persons)
    - Dorothy Richardson, n.d.,1917 (Box 11, Folder 319)
      At twelve months of age (4 copies) At school at Putney with classmates (2 copies) 1917 (negative in BRBL Photo File)
    - Dorothy Richardson and Alan Odle, 1924,1925,n.d. (Box 11, Folder 320)
      Dorothy Richardson in Peggy Kirkaldy's garden Dorothy Richardson and Alan smoking in garden with dog (2 copies) Dorothy Richardson and Alan smoking in garden with dog Alan leaning towards Dorothy Richardson Dorothy Richardson seated and Alan standing in garden, 1925 (2 copies)
      Alan seated in garden with dog Alan standing in garden Alan reclining in chaise longue in garden Dorothy Richardson, Alan, and Bryher in Reant Chateau garden, 1924 (2 copies) Portrait of Alan with wine glass and cigarette Portrait of Alan and Dorothy Richardson at table (painting by Adrian Allinson)
    - Dorothy Richardson's friends (Box 11, Folder 321)
      Harry Badcock (2 copies) Peggy Kirkaldy with 2 men John Cowper Powys, Ferner Nuhn, Ruth Suckow
    - Dorothy Richardson's relatives, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 322)
      Dorothy Richardson's grandmother Dorothy Richardson's father Rose Odle in garden
    - Dorothy Richardson's homes and haunts (Box 11, Folder 323)
      House in Hannover (2 copies) Dentist's office, Harley Street (2 copies) Skier finishing a long run (2 copies) Little Hampden, St. Missinden Mell Lane, Tollesbury Cornwall Dorothy Richardson's grave
    - Alan Odle's drawings, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 324)
      Untitled "The Infuriated Trousers"